A Guide to the Guy Davenport Papers, 1980-1982
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Guy Davenport Papers 1980-1982
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10539-k
73 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by the Library from Serendipity Books, on 1986 August 13.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of publisher Grey Fox's complete archive for The mimes of Herondas including correspondence with Davenport; a photocopy of the original typescript, and the setting copy, both with editorial corrections; a camera ready (blue line) copy; page proofs; miscellaneous proofs; paperback copy; and sample hardbound cover; together with an engraving plate for the spine.
Correspondence with Donald Allen, editor and publisher, deals with the writing, editing, and publishing of the book, including problems of translation, the responses of classic departments, journals and hostile reviewers, the history of mime, and the dramatic effect of some passages and Davenport's sketch for the cover, as well as bits of personal news.
Contents List
- Manuscripts 1980-1981
  - The Mimes of Herondas, translated by Guy Davenport, with autograph revisions by author and editor (electrostatic copy) 1980, TMs, 67 p.
  - The Mimes of Herondas (setting copy), with autograph revisions by author in ink and editor in pencil 1981, TMs, 82 p.
  - The Mimes of Herondas page proof, with ANS on first page and autograph revisions by author in pencil 1981, 67 p.
  - The Mimes of Herondas blue line print 1981, 3 folders, 77 p.
  - The Mimes of Herondas silverprint 1981, 77 p.
- Letters 1980-1982
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Donald Allen, Grey Fox Press, San Francisco, California, re doing a translation of Anacreon and Herondas 1980 October 23, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, re the need to reprint Herakleitos and Diogenes because of increased sales, and his willingness to publish the translation 1980 October 30, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, re having already sent corrections for the second printing of M & D and working on deciphering Anacreon and Herondas 1980 November 3, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, thanking him for the copies of books by poets [Jack ?] Spicer and [Philip?] Whalen 1980 November 7, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, asking questions about the manuscript translations of Herondas recently received 1980 December 16, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, indicating his belief that the Herondas is his best work, and re finishing other work 1980 December 18, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, agreeing that Herondas can go in a book by itself and planning to write the introductory essay 1980 December 20, TLS, 1 p.
  - (carbon) Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, discussing possible changes to the text of Herondas 1980 December 24, TL, 2 p. on 2 l.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, answering recent queries of the latter concerning the text 1980 December 27, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - (carbon) Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, sending along the contract(s) for publishing Herondas 1980 December 29, TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, including a new introduction and changes in the text 1981 January 2, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, enclosing a specimen setting in Palatino and discussing further the questions about the text 1981 January 6, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, returning a copy of the signed contract and discussing details in the new introduction and the text 1981 January 7, TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, expressing his pleasure in the typographer's work on the Palatino, further discussing the text, and saying he has had no luck in finding an image for the cover 1981 January 10, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, sending two original cover drawings and discussing further copy editing 1981 January 13, TLS, 2 p. on 2 l.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, suggesting a line drawing of a Greek figure for the cover (has not received prior letter), and accepting the offer of a list of plausible reviewers 1981 January 15, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, including a sketch of the cover within the body of the letter, and enclosing the blurb for the back cover 1981 January 17, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, revealing the typesetter's plan to go directly to page proofs 1981 February 6, TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, tying up loose ends on the Herondas 1981 February 9, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, re adding recent works to his biography 1981 February 10, TLS, 1 p.
  - (carbon) Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, sending the page proofs of "The Matchmaker" section of the Herondas 1981 February 17, TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, saying he is pleased with the page proofs and is sending some changes to the text (on a separate sheet) 1981 February 21, TLS, 2 p. on 2 l.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, writing with the news of his nomination for an American Book Award in Translation and his winning the American Academy and Institute Morton Dauwen Zabel Award for Fiction 1981 March 16, TLS, 1 p.
  - (carbon) Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, sending the galley proofs for checking 1981 March 26, TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, making some changes to the text after seeing the proofs 1981 April 2, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, re receiving the changes and possibly adding the recent awards to his biography 1981 April 5, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Donald Allen to "Bill, Antoinette and Gordon," re pagination of the separate mimes 1981 April 6, TLS, 1 p., 2 copies
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, answering questions about his recent awards 1981 April 9, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, commenting on French writers and sending information on translating Henry de Montherlant's plays [1981 April 17], TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, in answer to last letter, and re his plans to return to the Anacreon after finals 1981 April 21, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, mentioning the delay in pasting up pages for his book 1981 April 30, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, re losing the American Book Award 1981 May 5, APSC, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to "Bill," re changes in the typesetting of the Herondas 1981 June 24, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Donald Allen to Kathy King, sending the camera copy for the Herondas to be printed and bound, with instructions 1981 July 17, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, inquiring as to whether Herondas is in the press 1981 July 21, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, re arranging to send him paper and cloth copies of the Herondas 1981 August 5, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, requesting 10 cloth and 10 paper copies, with a bill 1981 August 10, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Kathy King, concerning one change to be made to the blue line print 1981 August 13, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, hoping that the Herondas will sell, especially with a couple good reviews 1981 August 25, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, re contributing to The Harvard Adovcate's issue on translators, and waiting for the copies 1981 August 27, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, agreeing that a mime from the Herondas should go to The Harvard Advocate 1981 September 2, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, expressing his pleasure with the printing of his book, and offering pieces to The Harvard Advocate 1981 September 5, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, thanking him for the "Griffin 'Conversations with Auden'," and mentioning a bad review by Hilton Kramer of his book 1981 September 5, TLS, 1 p.
  - (carbon) Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, discounting Hilton Kramer's credibility as a critic 1981 September 11, TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, writing that he was pleased that Allen was reading the Herondas for pleasure 1981 September 11, APCS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, writing that a film of the mimes could be done by "the crew that did 'La Cage aux Folles'" 1981 September 15, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, re having a radio review of the Herondas done by Jed Rasula on KPFK, and thanking him for the copy of [Michael ? ] Rumaker's latest book 1981 September 18, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, suggesting names of reviewers to receive copies of his book 1981 October 8, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, re having sent him ten copies of each edition of the Herondas 1981 November 3, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, with more witticisms on possible imitations of Herondas on film or stage 1981 November 6, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, writing that he sent a copy of the Herondas to The New Yorker for a review 1981 November 18, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, re a request from Barry S. Straus of Cornell for a copy of the Herondas for use as a text in his history class 1981 November 20, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, telling him that The New Yorker reviewer is George Steiner 1981 November 21, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, with miscellaneous questions and observations about the Herondas, in a light tone 1981 November 28, APCS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, sending a review of the Herondas by Harry Goldgar, and relaying the news that he heard Douglas Parker was working on an Herondas 1982 January 18, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, re recent reviews of the latter's works, with one attached from Choice 1982 January 18, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, expressing discontent over the review of the Herondas in Choice among others 1982 January 22, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Donald Allen, thanking him for the royalty check 1982 February 3, APCS, 1 p.
  - Donald Allen to Guy Davenport, commenting on the latter's letter to the editor of Choice 1982 February 24, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
- Miscellaneous
  - The Mimes of Herondas, translated by Guy Davenport: Miscellaneous texts for the book 1981, 4 items
  - Miscellaneous material for cover the The Mimes of Herondas 1981, 3 items
  - Printed, The Mimes of Herondas, translated by Guy Davenport 1981